sex.com 2010-06-07

# Sex.com - Site: Privacy Policy

Effective as of DECEMBER 11, 2008

Escom, LLC  is a licensee of the TRUSTe Web Privacy Seal Program.  TRUSTe is an independent, non-profit organization whose mission is to build user's trust and confidence in the Internet by promoting the use of fair information practices.  This privacy statement covers the Web site www.sex.com].  Because this Web site wants to demonstrate its commitment to your privacy, it has agreed to disclose its information practices and have its privacy practices reviewed for compliance by TRUSTe.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact **legal@escomllc.com**. If you do not receive acknowledgment of your inquiry or your inquiry has not been satisfactorily addressed, you should contact TRUSTe at <http://www.truste.org/consumers/watchdog_complaint.php> TRUSTe will then serve as a liaison with us to resolve your concerns

This website is located generally at **www.sex.com** and is the official website for **Sex.com** (the "Site"). This Site is owned and operated by **Escom, LLC** ("Escom" or "Owner and Operator").

Your privacy is very important to us. Because we gather certain types of personally identifiable information ("Personal Information") from users of our website, subscribers of our services and for various other operational and business purposes, we feel you should know how we collect, use, disclose, manage, and store the Personal Information that you may voluntarily provide us and the Personal Information that is collected passively through the use of cookies or image tags on our website. This Privacy Policy is incorporated by reference in the Site's Terms of Use Agreement, which is binding on all Site users. This Policy applies only to the Personal Information collected by Sex.com via the Site and does not govern any such information collected by its corporate parent(s), corporate affiliates ("Affiliates"), or any other company, unless specifically stated.

 **If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not participate in the online or off-line activities and services that require you to provide your Personal Information. (The type of Personal Information collected is listed below.)**

In order to ensure continued compliance with all applicable laws and fair information practices, where required, Sex.com agrees to cooperate with Integrity Services in good faith with respect to implementing any legally-required forms or language in its privacy policy and/or at the point where the Site collects any Online or Offline Records.   ??

To become a registered Member of the Site, you will be required to  submit at least your full name, zip code, a valid and functioning e-mail address, date of birth, username and password.  More information may be necessary in order for you to become a registered Member.  You agree and authorize us to provide the registration information you submit to an agency to confirm the accuracy of the information you submitted against public records.

This Policy provides information regarding your choices to either Opt-out or Opt-in when your Personal Information is used for various promotional and marketing purposes by Sex.com, the Site, its corporate affiliates, and/or our advertisers, sponsors, or promotional partners (collectively, "Advertisers").

 **YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS  
**  
Residents of the State of California that have an established business relationship with a company that conducts business in California, under a new provision of the California Civil Code, have the right to request from that company a list of all third parties to which the company has disclosed Personal Information about the resident for direct marketing purposes during the preceding year. Alternatively, the law provides that if the company has a privacy policy that gives either an Opt-out or Opt-in choice for use of Personal Information by third parties (such as Advertisers or Affiliates) for marketing purposes, the company may instead provide you with information on how to exercise your disclosure choice options.

This site qualifies for the alternative option; it has a comprehensive privacy policy and provides you with details on how you may Opt-out or Opt-in to the use of your Personal Information by third parties for direct marketing purposes. Therefore, we are not required to maintain or disclose a list of the third parties that received your Personal Information for marketing purposes during the preceding year.

If you are a California resident and have an established business relationship with us and want to receive information about how to exercise your third party disclosure choices you must send a request to the following address with a preference on how our response to your request should be sent (email or postal mail). You may contact us in two ways. Send email to Privacy Administrator at [privacy@sex.com](https://mail.google.com/mail?view=cm&tf=0&to=privacy@sex.com&su=message%20from%20privacy%20policy). Alternatively, you may contact Sex.com at:

**Escom, LLC**  
PO Box 1410  
Agoura Hills, CA  91376  
Attn: Your California Privacy Rights  
 **c/o Privacy Administrator**

**For requests sent via email, you must put the statement "Your California Privacy Rights" in the subject field of your email. All requests sent via postal mail must be labeled "Your California Privacy Rights" on the envelope or post card and clearly stated on the actual request.** For all requests, please include your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. (Your street address is optional if you wish to receive a response to your request via email. Please include your zip code for our own recordkeeping.) **We will not accept requests via the telephone or by facsimile.** We are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or not sent properly, or do not have complete information.

To all other users of this Site, if you have other questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact our Privacy Administrator at the following email address: [privacy@sex.com](https://mail.google.com/mail?view=cm&tf=0&to=privacy@sex.com&su=message%20from%20privacy%20policy%20page) or:

**Sex.com/Escom, LLC  
** PO Box 1410  
Agoura Hills, CA  91376  
Attn: Privacy Rights  
 **c/o Privacy Administrator  
**  
 **GENERAL PRIVACY GUIDELINES?**

**UNLESS SPECIFIED OTHERWISE ON THE SITE, ALL SUBSCRIBERS AND USERS OF THE SITE MUST BE AT LEAST 18 YEARS OF AGE AND A LEGAL RESIDENT OF THE UNITED STATES ("U.S.") TO SUBSCRIBE TO THE SERVICES PRESENTED ON THE SITE REQUIRING SUBMISSION OF PERSONAL INFORMATION. THIS SITE IS DESIGNED AND TARGETED TO U.S. AUDIENCES AND IS GOVERNED BY AND OPERATED IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE LAWS OF THE U.S. WE MAKE NO REPRESENTATION THAT THIS SITE IS OPERATED IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE LAWS OF OTHER NATIONS. BY YOUR PARTICIPATION IN OUR SITE ACTIVITIES, YOU CERTIFY THAT YOU ARE AT LEAST 18 YEARS OF AGE AND A LEGAL RESIDENT OF THE U.S. ALL USERS OF THE SITE ARE REQUIRED TO PROVIDE TRUE, CURRENT, COMPLETE AND ACCURATE PERSONAL INFORMATION WHEN PROMPTED AND WE WILL REJECT AND DELETE ANY ENTRY THAT WE BELIEVE IN GOOD FAITH TO BE FALSE, FRAUDULENT, OR INCONSISTENT WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY.**

Your continued participation on this Site indicates your acceptance of this Privacy Policy and of the collection, use, disclosure, management and storage of your Personal Information as described below. We may from time to time, transfer or merge any Personal Information collected off-line to our online databases or store off-line information in an electronic format. We may also combine Personal Information we collect online with information available from other sources, including information received from our corporate affiliates, Advertisers, or marketing companies. This Privacy Policy covers all such Personal Information and will remain in full force and effect as long as you are a user of the Site. We reserve the right to revise this Privacy Policy at any time by updating this document. All subscribers will be notified by electronic mail and a prominent posting on the Site of any material revisions to this document. Such revisions shall be effective to you immediately upon posting. We encourage you to read such emails and postings, and otherwise check this Privacy Policy often, to remain fully apprised or our privacy practices. By continued use of the Site and/or Service after you have been notified of any changes in this Privacy Policy, you indicate that you have freely consented to any such changes.

We use your Personal Information to provide you with the features, services, or goods you request, to respond to billing and/or other such questions related to Sex.com's services offered through the Site and to notify you about updates and new features that may be of interest to you. (We explain below in the next section what our policy is for the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information to Advertisers.)

We may also use your information for hiring, operational and business purposes, to find out how we can improve our services and your use of the Site via surveys or online tracking mechanisms, and to develop new services and features that may be of interest to you. We use aggregate Personal Information to help us to evaluate and modify existing services and features.

We will not sell, exchange, rent, lease or otherwise disclose your Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information to third party marketers or any such persons that are not associated with Sex.com as Advertisers unless it is necessary to: 1) conform to regulatory and legal requirements or to comply with legal process, judicial proceeding, warrant or subpoena; 2) to protect the safety and security of our users, employees, or property; 3) to defend the rights of the Site or Sex.com; or 4) to enforce the Terms of Use Agreement.

We will share your Personal Information with our subsidiaries, corporate parents, and Affiliates primarily for business, operational, promotional and marketing purposes.

It is also necessary that we share your Personal Information and Sensitive Personal Information with our operational service providers, the specialists that provide us with internal support for our operations and activities and/or for Site design, development, hosting and operations including maintenance, management, storage and/or fulfillment of our services and other activities.

We reserve the right to collect Personal Information using any new technology yet to be developed and to use such technology to provide new services and features to you, as well as for marketing and promotional purposes.

For purposes of this Privacy Policy, "Personal Information" shall refer to the following: your name, physical address, including city, and state, email address, telephone number, age or date of birth. "Sensitive Personal Information" shall refer to the following: your social security number, driver's license number or state identification card number, employee identification number, account number, credit or debit card number, with or without any required security code, access code or password that would permit access to an individual's financial account, mother's maiden name, passport number, or electronic or digitized signature.

 **BLOGS  
**  
If you use a bulletin board, blog, or chat room on this Web site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of these forums, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages.  We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in these forums.

 **DISCLOSURE TO ADVERTISERS  
**  
We may also use your Personal Information for the marketing of events, products or services of our Advertisers. There are two ways users may receive such information from Advertisers, either indirectly via newsletters, email or direct mail from the Site, or directly from the Advertiser. We may use one or both methods depending on the activity and the Advertiser.

We do not currently share Personal Information with our Advertisers. However, depending on the activity, we may in the future do so and you will receive notice on the Site and/or in the rules of participation ("Rules of Participation") for the event or activity, or via an email notice. Please be informed that our Advertisers may not have the same privacy policies that we do. Therefore, you will need to tell us if you do not want to receive marketing information directly from our Advertisers. You will need to check the "Opt-out" click boxes that may be included on the registration area for the particular event, in an email, or alternatively, notify the Site's Privacy Administrator at [privacy@sex.com](https://mail.google.com/mail?view=cm&tf=0&to=privacy@sex.com&su=message%20from%20privacy%20policy%20page). You will also need to tell us if you do not wish to receive marketing or promotional materials from the Site in the same manner.

We also provide you with an option to "Opt-out" of receiving advertising and promotional email from us in compliance with federal law by installing an Opt-out mechanism with all such email messages. You must use the designated method in the email message to notify us of your Opt-out request, as we cannot guarantee that other methods of notification will be effective or timely. Please be aware that we may continue to contact you via email for administrative or informational purposes, including follow-up messages regarding contests you have entered or other transactions you have undertaken. By law, such messages are not considered to be commercial email.

We use third party service providers to expedite credit card payments and to ship products to users who have purchased merchandise from our Site. 

We are not responsible for removing your Personal Information from third party lists or entities which you have previously authorized us to share your information. You will need to contact those entities directly.

 **COOKIES AND IMAGE TAGS  
**  
The use of cookies is an industry standard and they are currently used on most websites, including this Site. Cookies are a small text file containing a unique identification number that is transferred from a website server either to your browser or temporary storage of a user's computer so that the website administrator or a third party operational service provider may identify the computer and passively track the user's activities on the website. Image tags work in conjunction with cookies and are small image files that may be located on select pages of our Site, or within web-based email newsletters that we may send. (Image tags are also called web beacons, web bugs, clear GIFs or single-pixel GIFs.) Tracking is important because we can better understand what parts of our website are used the most, when to launch new services and how to enhance current offerings. We may share the information we receive from cookies and image tags with third parties and our Advertisers in aggregate form, which means that such information generally does not contain specific Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information about any one visitor. In short, cookies and image tags collect a user's Internet protocols and server information. Such data files allow our Site to remember your web browser when you visit our Site and are necessary tools for quick and efficient access to areas of our Site. A cookie will not allow the Site to learn any Personal Information (such as your real name and email address) or Sensitive Personal Information that you have not otherwise disclosed.

You should be aware that different rules might apply to the collection, use or disclosure of your Personal Information by other third parties in connection with their advertisements, promotions and other websites you encounter on the Internet. The use of cookies and other technology by these third parties is within their control and not ours. Even if we have a relationship with the third party, we do not control those sites or their policies and practices regarding your Personal Information. This Privacy Policy does not cover any use of Personal Information that a third party or an Advertiser may collect from you. We encourage you to investigate and ask questions directly of them in this regard.

 **ADVERTISING, OTHER THIRD PARTY CONTENT AND HYPERLINKS  
**  
This Privacy Policy does not cover third party advertising or third party content that may be present on the Site. This Site may provide banner and general advertising from third parties, in addition to other content provided by our Advertisers or operational service providers. Users may from time to time purchase goods or services offered through, or otherwise participate in or send messages concerning such advertising, promotions or third party content offered through the Site. Such correspondence, transactions and agreements are solely between the user and the Advertiser or the third party content provider and do not involve the Site. Also, Advertisers and such third party content providers may not have the same privacy policies that we do and you are encouraged to read their privacy policy first. (Also see our section called "Cookies and Image Tags")

This Site may provide links to third party websites that could be of interest to our users, including the websites of our Advertisers. Sex.com does not own or control these websites and therefore, is not responsible for the content, business practices, nor operations of such websites. Third party websites linked on this Site may have different privacy policies and business practices than we do. The presence of a link to a third party website does not constitute or imply our endorsement, recommendation, or sponsorship of the third party content, goods, or services available through, or contained on, the Site. By use of this Site, you have agreed that you will use the hyperlinks to third party sites at your own risk.

 **SECURITY MEASURES  
**  
We conduct the collection, management, maintenance and storage of listener or website user information in a secure and commercially reasonable manner using acceptable industry standards of security technology and practices to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of Personal Information. When a user enters sensitive information, such as a credit card number, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).  We also request that our operational service providers take such precautions. The www.Sex.com website databases are accessible only by authorized personnel.

However, please note that when users transmit Personal Information over an unsecured Internet connection, the Site is not responsible for the security of that information during the transmission stage as your email or registration could be copied or intercepted by unknown third parties. We use a secured connection only for the collection of Sensitive Personal Information, which is necessary for the purchase of goods or services, but we do not use a secured connection for other types of activities. Therefore, you understand, acknowledge, and agree that you transmit certain Personal Information over this Site at your own risk.

 **CHILDREN'S PRIVACY POLICY  
**  
Sex.com does not sell products or services for purchase by children. Sex.com does not knowingly solicit or collect Personal Information from children or teenagers under the age of eighteen. If you believe that a minor has disclosed Personal Information to Sex.com, please email [privacy@sex.com](https://mail.google.com/mail?view=cm&tf=0&to=privacy@sex.com&su=message%20from%20privacy%20policy%20page).

 **REVIEW, UPDATE, CORRECT, OR DELETE PERSONAL INFORMATION OR SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION  
**  
Generally, you may review, update or delete your Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information collected by the Site. You may also correct factual inaccuracies. Certain types of Personal Information that are necessary to check eligibility, such as birth date or age, cannot be deleted, but may be modified with sufficient verification of the new information. Note that we reserve the right to terminate or delete any membership or entry if we believe the Personal Information submitted was knowingly false or fraudulent.

To review, update or delete your Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information collected by the Site, please email the Site's Privacy Administrator at [privacy@sex.com](https://mail.google.com/mail?view=cm&tf=0&to=privacy@sex.com&su=message%20from%20privacy%20policy%20page), through the "Account Settings" page of your user account, or click here. In addition, To have access to your Personal Information or Sensitive Personal Information, you must provide proof of identification such as full name, street address, city/state and zip code, user ID and password, and/or information about your recent activity on the website. We reserve the right to deny access to any user if we believe there is a question about your identity. And if the burden or expense of providing access to your Personal Information is disproportionate to the risks to your privacy, or if the legitimate rights of others would be violated, we may decide not to provide access to such information. In such cases, we will provide to you an explanation of why access cannot be provided and a contact person for further inquiries.

This Privacy Policy was last updated on December 11, 2009 and is effective immediately.
